Jon Beaulieu

IoT Software Engineer & Project Manager

contact@jonbeaulieu.com Milwaukee, WI LinkedIn

ABOUT ME

Experienced software developer and project manager with a history of successfully developing and launching IoT products. Skilled in current cloud/edge technologies, and well-versed in enacting standards and best practices for connected devices. Always exited to hear about new opportunities in the IoT, particularly those with exposure to cloud services and mobile tech.

EDUCATION

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science (2017)

Electrical Engineering & Computer Science

SKILLS

Software Languages

- C#, .NET Framework
- Node.js
- React
- Python
- JavaScript

Technologies

- Android, iOS
- Microsoft Azure
- Docker, microservices
- Kubernetes

Design

- UI / UX design
- User testing
- Adobe Creative Cloud

EXPERIENCE

Senior IoT Software Engineer

2021 – Present

Zego

Milwaukee, WI (Remote)

- Worked as part of an agile team to support and design new features for Zego's property management web platforms.
- Evaluated new IoT hardware and created development plans to integrate new functionality into Zego Smart, a residential smart-home application.
- Developed new AWS-based services in Node.js and Elixir to better support smart-home products for residential customers.

IoT Program Leader

2019 - 2020

Regal Beloit Corporation

Milwaukee, WI

- Led a New Product Development team responsible for designing and testing commercial IoT prototypes and identifying potential business opportunities.
- Established standards for code development, version control, and cloud communication for connected products.
- Supervised implementation of an Azure-based platform to unify Regal IoT products under a single cloud infrastructure.
- Served as the project manager for the design and launch of a modular IoT solution to give connected capabilities to existing commercial products.

Software Design Engineer

2017 - 2019

Regal Beloit Corporation

Milwaukee, WI

- Designed several proof-of-concept IoT solutions to demonstrate connectivity, including a digital user interface for commercial motor products, a Node.js web platform to aggregate data, and a mobile app to give insights to users.
- Developed a series of APIs to migrate a legacy IoT product to a new cloud platform while maintaining connectivity for existing users. Co-developed a redesign of iOS and Android apps to provide a better user experience.

Enterprise Architecture & Security Intern

2016 – 2017

MIT Information Systems & Technology

Cambridge, MA

- Designed new APIs to promote better data policies between academic depts.
- Developed a series of Python scripts to streamline collection of security records.